Video by Mario Ducoing
Used with permission
PREQ1939
Video Subtitles and
Captioning Support
PREQ1939 is complete
and available today.
It is officially in Symbian OS
Diran only, but the code is
present in 9.5 releases and is
easy to enable and build.
This demo runs under a stock
Symbian OS 9.5 DevKit release.
We have simply enabled NGA,
enabled PREQ1939,
rebuilt MMF, and added a
simple demo application.
Detailed build info
and this demo application is
available on request.
PREQ1939 requires that video
playback uses graphics surfaces.
The actual subtitles however
are rendered as UI graphics
Using a Content Rendering
Plugin (CRP) in Window Server.
The PREQ delivery includes all
MMF and API changes,
a product-quality CRP for
subtitle rendering,
and a reference SRT subtitle
renderer in the AVI controller.
This demo uses a video-only
AVI file with MPEG-4 video
and a hand-written SRT
subtitle file.
Real-world implementations
are expected to use
3GPP Timed Text instead.
In any case, all subtitles are
rendered in the controller and
displayed directly using a CRP.
The application is not on the
data path at all, and has only
basic control functionality.
Thank you