cenrep
version 1

#
# 1020497A.txt
# Test config file for central repository
# Specifies A2DP BT Headset address
#

[platsec]
# default capabilities for this repository
# Note: The default capability for writing should be WriteDeviceData but
#       this is not currently activated. See release notes for details.
cap_rd=MultimediaDD cap_wr=MultimediaDD

[main]
#A2DP Bluetooth headset address - must be hex with no 0x
#CSR test board
1 string "00025B018B56" 0
#Blue ant headset
#1 string "000A5600B9DD" 0
