LUCIO SILLA
O heaven,
my friend Cinna
I await here in vain.
My impatience
Grows with his delaying.
Alas,
how wearisome
Is each moment (Lucio Silla(K135) is an Italian opera in three acts composed by Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart. The libretto was written by Giovanni de Gamerra. It was first performed on 26 December 1772 at the Regio Ducal Teatro in Milan. Another opera by the same title was also done in 1774 by Pasquale Anfossi. The story concerns the Roman dictator Lucio Silla (Lucius Sulla) who lusts after Giunia, the daughter of his enemy Caius Marius. Giunia, on the other hand, loves the exiled senator Cecilio. Role: Lucio Silla (Lucius Cornelius Sulla), dictator of Rome; Celia, sister of Lucio Silla; Giunia (Junia), betrothed to Cecilio; Cecilio (Cecilius), Roman senator in exile; Lucio (Lucius) Cinna, friend of Cecilio; Aufidio (Aufidius), tribune and friend of Lucio Silla; Guards, nobles, senators, people (chorus). "Dalla sponda tenebrosa" - Giunia in Act I; "Il desio di vendetta" - Silla in Act I; "Il tenero momento" - Cecilio in Act I; "Se lusinghiera speme" - Celia in Act I; "Vieni ov'amor t'invita" - Lucio Cinna in Act I; "Guerrier che d'un acciaro" - Aufidio in Act II; "Nel fortunato istante" - Lucio Cinna in Act II; "Parto, m'affretto" - Giunia in Act II; "Ah se a morir" - Cecilio in Act II; "Ah se il crudel periglio" - Giunia in Act II; "D'ogni pieta mi spoglio" - Silla in Act II; "Quando sugl'arsi campi" - Celia in Act II; "Quest' improvviso tremito" - Cecilio in Act II; "Se il labbro timido" - Celia in Act II; "De piu superbi il core" - Lucio Cinna in Act III; "Fra i pensier" - Giunia in Act III; "Pupille amate" - Cecilio in Act III; "Strider sento la procella" - Celia in Act III)
For the human heart,
when doubts,
Waver betwixt hope and fear...
But, am I not misled?
He comes! The gods be praised!
LUCIO SILLA by W.A.Mozart